<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>programming on Bonkowski.net</title>
    <link>https://bonkowski.net/categories/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in programming on Bonkowski.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 17:54:10 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bonkowski.net/categories/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Serverside Swift</title>
      <link>https://bonkowski.net/posts/serverside-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 17:54:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bonkowski.net/posts/serverside-swift/</guid>
      <description>I found this article today on raywenderlich.com, which was fun since I last night started playing around a little with Swift on the server-side.
To be able to use Swift on the server-side appeals to me because I really like the language. As earlier mentioned, I started looking into this last night, wanting to replicate a &amp;ldquo;Mock&amp;rdquo; server written in Go, just for fun. This server makes it easy for us to simulate a real environment while developing our iOS and Android apps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yesql, Oracle and fetch out of sequence</title>
      <link>https://bonkowski.net/posts/yesql-oracle-and-fetch-out-of-sequence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 22:08:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bonkowski.net/posts/yesql-oracle-and-fetch-out-of-sequence/</guid>
      <description>If you encounter an ‘ORA-01002: fetch out of sequence’ when running your Yesql functions, make sure you have remembered the exclamation mark after the name of your insert/update/delete. I have only used Oracle with Yesql, but I expect other databases will give a similar error if you forget this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refactoring in AppCode</title>
      <link>https://bonkowski.net/posts/refactoring-in-appcode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2013 23:19:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bonkowski.net/posts/refactoring-in-appcode/</guid>
      <description>AppCode offers a rich set of refactoring&amp;rsquo;s, which is fast, safe, and easy to use.
Rename Naming is surprisingly difficult. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to get &amp;ldquo;paralyzed&amp;rdquo; if the perfect name of a class or method does not pops into place immediately. But hey, you can always rename it later!
The &amp;ldquo;Rename&amp;rdquo; refactoring in AppCode is triggered by the shortcut &amp;#x21E7;F6. By using this, you can rename a file, class, method, property, ivar, local variable, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigation in AppCode (EAP)</title>
      <link>https://bonkowski.net/posts/navigation-in-appcode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 21:32:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bonkowski.net/posts/navigation-in-appcode/</guid>
      <description>Xcode My first meeting with Xcode, which was version 3 something, did not impress me. A couple of years later, Xcode 4 was presented at WWDC 2010, and while my first impression was positive, this feeling was short lived. It crashed continually, and while it looked good, which it still does, the editing experience and feature set were far below my expectations for a modern IDE.
JetBrains I know that more than 10 years experience with IDE&amp;rsquo;s from JetBrains, such as IntelliJ and RubyMine, does something with your expectations of what an IDE should provide.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>